Register of the Boutros Boutros-Ghali papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Boutros-Ghali Family Archive, 1867-1982 (Boxes 247-279)
  - Z/5. Report on the Sudan by Aziz Ezzat Pasha addressed to Wacyf Boutros Ghali, 1924 (Box-folder 279: 20)
  - Newspaper articles on the Coptic questions, 1912 (Box-folder 279: 21)
  - Biography of Boghos Bey Yassoufian (1768-1844) by Yacoub Artin Pasha, undated (Box-folder 279: 22)
- Audiovisual File, 1993-1996 (Boxes 280-288)
  Includes VHS videotapes, compact cassette tape, and floppy disk. Arranged by physical form, then chronologically thereunder.
  - Video recordings, 1993-1996
    Unless otherwise specified, all tapes are VHS.
    - 1993
      - Interview with the secretary general (SG) by Hamdy Fouad, Egyptian TV, January 26 (Box 280)
      - "The MacNeil-Lehrer News Hour," Channel 13, January 27 (Box 280)
      - "Togo: Constitutional Crisis. Address of the president (January 13) and press conference of prime minister (February 12),", January-February (Box 280)
      - Press briefing of U.S. Secretary of State Warren Christopher regarding support of U.S. administration for Vance-Owen Plan for Bosnia, CNN (Box 280)
      - "Management and Mismanagement at the UN," hearing of D. Thornburgh (USG) at the U.S. Congress Subcommittee for International Security and Human Rights, March 3 (Box 280)
        2 tapes.
      - "SG's statement on Cambodia and statement to political parties,", April 8 (Box 280)
      - "SG on Cambodia and elections in Vietnam,", April 16 (Box 280)
        Beta SP tape.
      - "Cambodia: William Shawcross," Assignment BBC, April 20 (Box 280)
      - Interview with the SG, Sky TV, April 24 (Box 280)
      - Interview with the SG by David Frost, April 30 (Box 280)
      - "The MacNeil-Lehrer News Hour" on Somalia, Channel 13, May 1 (Box 280)
      - "Zeitpunkt," interview with the SG for German television, May 19 (Box 280)
      - "CNN aircheck,", May 25 (Box 280, Box 281)
      - SG's visit to Morocco (Arabic), May 31 (Box 281)
      - "Peacekeeping Around the World," hearing at the U.S. Senate Foreign Relations Committee with Madeleine Albright (U.S. Perm. Representative), Paul Volcker (UN adviser) and Brian Urquhart, C-SPAN II, June 9 (Box 281)
      - SG's visit to UN headquarters in Cairo regarding awarding of Peace Medal to Krishna Thapa (Major General UNTSO), Video Cairo, June 27 (Box 281)
      - Interview with the SG by Jean Frocois Lepine, "Le Point" CBC, August 22 (Box 281)
      - Canada "A.M." interview with Boutros Boutros-Ghali, August 24 (Box 281)
      - "La Marche du Siècle: Boutros Boutros-Ghali,", September 1 (Box 281)
      - "World News" CNN feature on Somalia, October 11 (Box 281)
      - SG's speech upon arrival in Nairobi, Kenya, October 20 (Box 281)
      - Opening ceremony of the UN Day exhibit at the Theatre National, Med V, Rabat, Morocco, October 24 (Box 281)
      - "News Night," UN item and interview, October 25 (Box 281)
      - SG's visit to West Point, "Diplomatic License," CNN, November 19 (Box 282)
      - "On Budget," Current Affair, December 10 (Box 282)
      - "Diplomatic License," CNN, December 31 (Box 282)
      - BBC World Review-United Nations (Jon Leyne), December (Box 282)
    - 1994
      - NHK prior to visit to Japan, February 5 (Box 282)
      - "LA Times Breakfast,", February 11 (Box 282)
      - Interview with the SG on President's Day, Egyptian TV, February 21 (Box 282)
      - Interview with the SG, February 21 (Box 282)
      - "5th Estate" and "Bad Business at the UN," Canada Broadcasting Corporation, March 1 (Box 282)
      - ABC "Nightline" interview with the SG, May 4 (Box 282)
      - CR4, SG press conference, May 25 (Box 282)
        5 tapes.
      - Interview with SG, MBC London, May 25 (Box 282)
      - Three reports on the UN by Aziz Fahmy Farag, MBC New York, June (Box 282)
      - United Nations International Conference on Population and Development, July 25 (Box 283)
      - Haiti special, July 27 (Box 283)
      - SG profile, UN Videos, August 3 (Box 283)
      - "Arabic news bulletin,", August 18 (Box 283)
      - Interview with SG, "Le Point," Canadian Broadcasting Corporation, August 22 (Box 283)
      - "SG statement to David Rockefeller," UN-TV, September 9 (Box 283)
      - "The Rockefeller Gift," BCUN, September 9 (Box 283)
      - "Interview of Dr. Boutros Boutros-Ghali by Ashis Ray of CNN,", September 9 (Box 283)
      - NHK interview with SG, September 11 (Box 283)
      - "SG Statement on Disaster (Italy),", September 12 (Box 283)
      - "Interview with SG (Tokyo),", September 12 (Box 283)
      - "Interview with SG the day after signing the agreement on Beijing Conference on Women," CCTV (Chinese TV), September 15 (Box 283)
      - "Sudan: Africa's Holy War," BBC WSTV, October (Box 284)
      - "La Radio qui tue" (October 7); "Le Retour des Tutsis" (October 19); "Minuar" (November 15), "Le Point" (Canada), October-November (Box 284)
        Series of reports on Rwanda featuring Oakley (former SGSR Somalia), Thornburgh, E. Luck (US-UN Association), R. Dallaire (Ex-Commander), and Sh. Khan (SGSR).
      - "Seeds of Peace," promotional tape about the meeting of Arab and Jewish children, October 11 (Box 284)
      - Charlie Rose interview with SG, October 20 (Box 284)
        3 tapes.
      - CBC 5th Estate, "Fighting Back" (Skylink affair), November 8 (Box 284)
      - "Diplomatic License," CNN, December 4 (Box 284)
      - Interview with the SG by Charlane Hunter-Gall, "MacNeil-Lehrer News Hour," Channel 21 (USA), December 12 (Box 284)
      - "UN Blues" documentary: Tape 1, "The First Betrayal" (UN and McCarthyism); Tape 2, "The Sleaze Factor" (Mismanagement at the UN, WHO, Arrears); Tape 3, "The Peacemongers" (UN Missions in Africa), December 20 (Box 284)
      - Interview with Slobodan Milosevic, "Larry King Live," CNN, December 21 (Box 284)
    - 1995
      - "Diplomatic License," CNN, January (Box 284)
      - SG press conference at UN headquarters, UN-TV, January 5 (Box 285)
      - "Global" and "The UN - Myth and Reality" with Khaled Khali (director of UNIS), I. Razali (Malaysian Perm. Representative), Malaysian TV, January 20 (Box 285)
      - Coverage of the SG's visit to Haiti, UN-TV, March 30 (Box 285)
      - "Headline News" coverage of SG in Haiti, CNN, March 30 (Box 285)
      - Coverage of SG's visit to Fiji, May (Box 285)
      - "UN 50th Project" (Inspection- Agenda for Peace), NHK ETV-Special, May 2 (Box 285)
      - Secretary General, May 4 (Box 285)
      - "We" featuring the SG, Public Russian TV, May 15 (Box 285)
      - SG statement at the Yokohama Conference on Natural Disaster Reduction, May 23 (Box 285)
      - "MacNeil-Lehrer News Hour" interview with SG, Channel 25, June 2 (Box 285)
      - "50 Years United Nations," German TV, June 29 (Box 285)
      - "United Nations 50th Anniversary Arabic,", June 29 (Box 285)
      - Interview with SG by Alexandra Spanidaki-Anastassiou, Antenna TV (Greek) (Box 286)
      - "International Conference on Mine Clearance--Excerpts of Statement by the UN SG,", July 28 (Box 286)
      - "Eyewitness News Conference: UN Ambassadors,", October 29 (Box 286)
      - "Charlie Rose: Boutros-Ghali/Avedon/Donald,", November 1 (Box 286)
      - Euronews "Prisma"- Interview with UN SG Boutros Boutros-Ghali, November 18 (Box 286)
      - "World Leaders Lecture Speech by Boutros Boutros-Ghali,", November 22 (Box 286)
      - "Temps Présent--L'O.N.U. Malgre Tout,", November 23 (Box 286)
      - Press conference with the SG, December 18 (Box 286)
    - 1996
      - "Cyril Foster Lecture,", January 15 (Box 286)
      - "Newsdesk-Brian Hanrahan interview with SG Boutros Boutros-Ghali,", January 15 (Box 286)
      - "Interview of the SG with Moufid Fawzi,", January 25 (Box 286)
      - "Turner Educational Services Programmes AM and PM from the GA Hall etc.,", February 9 (Box 286)
      - "CNN World Report-Global Forum with UN SG Boutros Boutros-Ghali,", May 16 (Box 286)
      - "Diplomatic License: Habitat II: Interview with the SG,", June 3-14 (Box 286)
      - "The Changing Role of the United Nations," Uncommon Knowledge series 1, no. 13, featuring Charles Hill and Stephen Stedman, September 21 (Box 287)
      - Press conference, Kuwait, December 28 (Box 287)
      - "Boutros Boutros-Ghali Un-edited Interview,", 1996 (Box 287)
      - "Address of UN SG Boutros Boutros-Ghali to the 1996 European International Model United Nations," (Box 287)
    - Undated
      - "Aller simple pour l'espoir," CAPA docmentary on migration flows featuring UN Development Program Mahbub Ul Haq (Box 287)
      - "BBC Assignment Mission Impossible: Interview with the SG on Somalia" (Box 287)
      - "BBC Assignment (Somalia)" (Box 287)
      - "Boutros Boutros-Ghali-Dub of Rushes Tape 40" (Box 287)
      - "Canada: Great Lakes" (Box 287)
      - "Communion of Nations" (International Catholic Organizations Information Center) (Box 287)
      - "CSPAN Sunday Journal Interview with Michael Stopford (Director General of UNIC-Washington) by Jim Mills" (Box 287)
      - "David Letterman Show-'The 10 Most Singable Names' (Boutros Boutros-Ghali Number 1)" (Box 287)
      - "E. Lindenmeyer on Somalia" (Box 287)
      - "Evolution de la crise Togolaise" (Box 287)
      - "Geopolis" (documentary series); "Voyage en ONUsie" (Documentary on the UN), France 2 (Box 287)
      - MBC interview with SG by Aziz Fahmy Farag (Box 288)
      - Promotional tape, VOX Film-TV (Box 288)
      - "Riza story on NY 1" (Box 288)
      - SG Report on Bosnia, "La Bar de Bebbette Show," La Chaine Info-France (Satire) (Box 288)
      - SG Tokyo statement (Box 288)
      - UN Day film: "Child of One Earth" (Box 288)
      - "University for Peace" (Box 288)
  - Compact sound cassette, "Secretary General on U.S. Campaign to [illegible],", 1996 December 1 (Box 288)
  - Computer disks, "Cambodia documents,", undated (Box 288)
    2 3.5-inch floppy disks.
- Oversize Materials, 1970s, 1990s (Oversize-box 289)
  - Boutros Boutros-Ghali Egyptian campaign poster, 1970s
  - Mexican magazine, Siempre, with cover story on Boutros Boutros-Ghali, 1992
  - United Nations 50th anniversary celebration photograph, 1995
  - Certificate to the United Nations from Massachusetts House of Representatives in recognition of receiveing the world organization study club's 22nd annual world diplomat award, 1992 May 1
  - Small satirical poster of Boutros Boutros-Ghali, undated
- Declassified Government Records, 1880, 1990s (Box 279)
  Formerly security-classified records of the U.S. government, released in full or in part. Arranged chronologically by date of release by Hoover.
  - 2013 release of records, 1880 (Box-folder 279: 23)
    Includes one document [photocopy] titled "Memorandum Respecting the Naturalization of Ottoman Subjects as Hellenic Subjects," printed for the use of the Foreign Office, February 20, 1880.
  - 2015 July release of records, 1990, 1993, undated (Box-folder 279: 24)
    Includes three documents:
    A copy of an undated message from George P. Shultz that references Charles Hill with the subject "Draft report of the Secretary's meeting with Prime Minister Shamir February 29."
    A 20 December 1990 letter from Frank G. Wisner at the Embassy of the United States of America in Cairo to Dr. Boutros-Ghali.
    A copy of a speech given by Secretary of State Warren Christopher on 20 September 1993 titled "Somalia: Where Do We Go From Here."